in my opinion I don't think shbg is a
big factor for injection frequency now
there are some pretty good arguments
against that and I recognize those
arguments I just don't think they hold
as much weight in the decision as uh
they should so or they are made out to
be sorry um I think that people should
inject as often as they will and for
most people that's three three times a
week it's hard to get people to do daily
injections long term if people will do
daily injections long term if they're
you know particularly disciplined they
like to do the same thing every day
they're like very routine based great
great fantastic most people won't do
that when it comes to like a g pop thing
like when you're working with people in
a clinic who've just been on Google and
found you even getting them to do twice
a week can be difficult um really
difficult so I like people to inject as
often as they will
um when it comes to
shbg my general stance on it is that the
lower the shbg the more often you need
to inject so if you've got an shbg like
under 20 then you really need to inject
more often but I would still argue that
even if you have an shbg of 5060 then
you would still benefit from injecting
just as often it just might not be as
necessary for you to do and the reason
is and I I would love to hear a
counterargument to this respectfully of
course is that shbg doesn't impact the
half life of the Esther and the half
life of the Esther is the primary thing
that determines injection frequency as
far as I'm aware shbg also doesn't
impact the peak time of the medication
either so when it comes to shbg I think
shbg is more important for determining
the free testosterone level because
that's going be the primary thing that
impacts how much free is Unbound from
Total um which is I don't think that can
really be refuted I mean everyone has to
agree with that because that's a
scientific fact but when it comes to
frequency I don't think that well at
least as far as I'm aware I think that
old argument that if you have high shbg
you want to inject less often to push it
down I I think that's kind of Gone With
the Wind at this stage I think that was
a Bro Science thing that's kind of died
but maybe I'm wrong with that but I
think that shbg is a little bit of a red
herring when it comes to injection
frequency I think we should all inject
as often as we will because male hormone
replacement therapy the number one
priority from a clinical outcome
standpoint is stability men do well with
a daily hormonal Rhythm we don't do well
with you know weekly or monthly hormonal
rhythms not to offend anyone I don't
think women do particularly well with
them either but that's the way they're
designed um um I don't think anyone does
well with with hormone fluctuation so
stability is King I think shbg is
important for determining dose but I
think that the lower your shbg the more
often you have to inject but I think
everyone should inject more often
regardless I don't think serum estral
has anything to do with injection
frequency so the best option is just to
switch to cream then or switch to cream
yeah well the great thing about cream is
cream allows you to do twice daily
administ ation um that's one of the best
things about cream is that you can have
Ultra stable levels and you know twice
daily cream delivers the same stability
that will people will get with daily
injections and um daily injections are
great if people will do them but if you
don't respond well to subcutaneous
injections and you have to do
intramuscular which I think most people
are in that camp people aren't going to
do that longterm novelty wears off it's
not people AR
[Music]
he